The rich have always fed off the poor. This time, it's for real.
Society is a comedy, horror, mystery film directed by Brian Yuzna.
Bill Whitney is worried that he is different to his sister and parents.
They mix with other upper-class people while Bill is more down to earth.
Even his girlfriend seems a bit odd.
All is revealed when Bill returns home to find a party in full swing.
Bill Whitney, played by Billy Warlock.
Nan, played by Connie Danese.
Dr. Cleveland, played by Ben Slack.
Milo, played by Evan Richards.
Jenny Whitney, played by Patrice Jennings.
David Blanchard, played by Tim Bartell.
Society is a 1989 American body horror film directed by Brian Yuzna in his
directorial debut from a screenplay by Woody Keith and Rick Fry.
It stars Billy Warlock as a teenager in Beverly Hills who begins to suspect that his
wealthy parents are part of a gruesome cult made up of the social elite.
Society was originally conceived as a more conventional slasher, featuring
a cult of social elitists who engage in human sacrifice.
The screenplay was reshaped by Yuzna, who introduced body horror elements such as the reveal of the cult being a
shapeshifting species that can literally feed on the lower classes, a concept he based on nightmares he had experienced.
The film was shot in California in 1988 with Screaming Mad
George as the special effects designer.
The film screened at the 1989 Cannes Film Festival, but went
unreleased in the United States until 1992.
It failed commercially, though it received critical
acclaim from international audiences.
In the years since its release, the film has garnered a cult
following and is regarded as influential in body horror.
The film explores themes of high school, orgy,
transformation, secret society, cult.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.